nevertheless this is the shadiest
i've ever seen in fitness
is it even legal to just fabricate
anatomy like why stop at just three
muscles like if it's legal to just
fabricate human anatomy think about the
possibilities you know
i want to show you my new glute program
and it has seven regions of the glutes
and you need to perform a specific
exercise to develop every region and
then some other glute guru comes up and
is like his program only targets seven
regions my program
targets all 21 gluteal muscles and then
they just make up
where those muscles
take one 2009 was the year that i
decided
to enter the online fitness space i
started a blog
i started selling an e-book i started
writing for tnation
i started using facebook twitter and
youtube and around this same time
beachbody created this product called
brazil butt lift now for those of you
who don't know about beachbody they're
most known for p90x but around the same
time i entered the fitness space at
around 2009
an infomercial started being aired and
this was known as brazil butt lift now
this is not to be confused with the
brazilian butt lift or the bbl
which became very common in fact if you
google you get a bunch of leads for the
surgery that many women are getting
today
but brazil butt lift predated that and
it was kind of a dance routine
started by this leandro carvalho and he
allegedly trained all these victoria's
secret models and
gave them their nice butts and the
program looks pretty interesting
it doesn't involve heavy resistance
training so it's not right down my alley
but what i like about it
is that it focuses on hitting a lot of
different angles you see a ton of
variety in
at least in the infomercial i never
watched or purchased the program
but enough banter now for the real
reason for this video
there's only one muscle it's the butt
it's three major muscles you have the
glute medius
maximus and minimus and all these three
muscles
they go in different directions so you
have to have all these different
exercises to hit the muscle in many
areas
leandro knows a woman's body like no
other it's
it's amazing i think he is the absolute
butt master
he knows everything there is to know
about your butt so the video highlights
leandra's unique method which he calls
triangle training to sculpt the glutes
sounds pretty cool right
now you can google triangle training
glutes and you'll see images pop up like
this
and when you look at this it quickly
becomes apparent to anybody who's ever
taken
an anatomy physiology class that the
muscular anatomy of the glutes doesn't
add up
this is just straight up fabricated
anatomy in the picture you got the glute
medius up here
the glute max here and the glute minimus
down here now in real life
the glute minimus is underneath the
glute medius and they form the upper
outer glutes and then the glute max lays
on top of them
and forms the lower glutes so my friend
bj godor used to work for men's health
and he worked with me on an article for
the glutes and it was funny they came to
me with a similar image
as what beachbody used and i was like no
no no no that's not accurate bj you got
to have them do it right
you have to draw this right it's a big
pet peeve of mine so men's health
created an accurate image
which i'll show here and leave up this
image from beachbody
so you can compare the differences now i
first wrote about this in 2013
so this was eight years ago and it never
slowed beachbody down they kept
promoting
brazil butt lift my guess is they quit
promoting because it just got old or the
term brazilian butt lift
for the surgery became so popular that
they just quit promoting the infomercial
nevertheless this is the shadiest
i've ever seen
in fitness is it even legal to just
fabricate anatomy like why stop at just
three muscles like if it's legal to just
fabricate human anatomy think about the
possibilities you know
i want to show you my new glute program
and it has seven regions of the glutes
and you need to perform a specific
exercise
to develop every region and then some
other glute guru comes up and is like
his program only targets seven regions
my program
targets all 21 gluteal muscles and then
they just make up
where those muscles like a puzzle right
like a jigsaw puzzle you just make up
how those muscles fall into place the
gluteus minimus is not the lower glute
there's an
upper and lower subdivision of the
gluteus maximus and there are posterior
middle and anterior
heads for both the gluteus medius and
the gluteus minimus
so three glute muscles eight
subdivisions total the main point of
this video is to educate my audience
and hopefully make you more alert to
infomercials and advertisements because
marketers can become
pretty sleazy and it really bugs me
because i'm a personal trainer but i do
have my phd
you know i've published 50 studies and i
try to be as evidence-based as possible
and what people do you think would be
best suited to make up pseudoscience
he'd be the legit scientist you know if
some of my buddies and i
decided to turn to the dark side and
just sell out and see how much money we
could possibly make by just
making stuff up and fabricating things
and just and using our scientific
knowledge to fool people
into believing fake science we could
have a field day but the vast majority
of scientists have a code of ethics
i couldn't do it i can't go there you
know i would never even think about it i
wouldn't be able to sleep at night
so shame on you to beachbody i'm sure
leandro's program is nice it's fun it's
probably pretty effective as far as like
dance routines go
but you never fabricate anatomy i
realize all these big companies all they
care about is money how bad would the
world
suck if there were no laws if there was
no truth in advertising i mean why not
just make up all the muscles and
subdivisions of the muscles and claim to
have a special exercise for every region
and why stop there why not claim that
spot reduction is legit
and say i've got a special exercise to
burn fat in every single region
and while you're at it claim to have a
solution for hip dips and banana rolls
in the thigh gap
and saddle bags if you watch my last
video you'll hear about gluteal amnesia
he'll claim to have a cure for gluteal
amnesia a problem that doesn't really
exist but sounds scary
nevertheless i sleep well at night
knowing that i don't have to go there
but i thought you'd find this amusing
it's literally the shadiest i've
ever seen in fitness
and i've seen a lot of if you
like this video please make sure to hit
like
if you think you've seen something even
shadier let me know about it in the
comments
and of course please subscribe to my
channel thanks for watching
now if this video intrigued you and you
would like to train
under my system using my principles then
i invite you to click on the link below
and subscribe to booty by brett
and join the thousands of other happy
members who are seeing amazing results